Guide to the Jon Butler Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1973-2004; Series IV
  - Articles, review essays, and book chapters
    - "American Witchcraft Reader: Witchcraft, Magic, Astrology and Alchemy in America, 1600-1800, " Butler, editor, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Bicentennial newspaper articles by Butler and colleagues, 1975-1976 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - "Enlarging the Bonds of Jesus", 1983 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - "Future of American Religious History," (WMQ version), 1984 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - "Huguenot Migration to South Carolina", 1985-1987 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - "Jacob Rader Marcus and the Revival of Early American History, 1930-1960", 1999-2000 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - "Les 'Hymnes ou cantiques sacrez' d'Elie Neau," Bulletin de la société de l'histoire du protestantisme français (BSHPF), 1978 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Keithian article, William and Mary Quarterly, 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - "Keithians of Pennsylvania", 1994-1996, undated (Box 22, Folder 10-11)
    - Religion in American History: A Reader, edited by Butler and Stout, 1983, 1988, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - "Sir Walter Raleigh in Defense of Quaker Orthodoxy: A Phineas Pemberton Letter of 1694," Quaker History, 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - "Spiritual Importance of the Eighteenth Century," In Search of Peace and Prosperity (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - "Spiritual Jack-in-the-Box," Journal of American History, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - "Thomas Teackle's 333 Books: A Great Library on Virginia's Eastern Shore, 1697," correspondence and research material, 1993, undated (Box 23, Folder 5-11)
    - "Three Minds, Three Books, Three Years: Reinhold Niebuhr, Perry Miller, and Mordecai Kaplan on Religion," intro, JAC, 2004, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - "Two 1642 Letters from Virginia Puritans," edited by Butler, Proceedings, Massachusetts Historical Society, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - "Whitefield in America", 1989 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Unpublished articles, 1974-1978, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 4-5)
  - Books and edited volumes
    Files contain materials related to Butler's works, including outlines; synopses; drafts; publicity; readers' reports and responses; reviews, correspondence with publishers; research materials; jacket cover designs; permissions; and similar items. Contents of folders may vary from book to book.
    - Awash in a Sea of Faith: Christianizing the American People, 1974-1993 (Box 24, Folder 6-13)
    - Becoming America: The Revolution Before 1776, 2000-2002 (Box 25, Folder 1-6)
    - The Huguenots in America: A Refugee People in New World Society, 1976-1998 (Box 25, Folder 7-10)
    - The Huguenots in America: A Refugee People in New World Society, 1984-1995 (Box 26, Folder 1-4)
    - Power, Authority and the Origins of American Denominational Order: The English Churches in the Delaware Valley, 1680-1730, 1976-1986 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
    - Religion in American Life, 1994-2001 (Box 27, Folder 3-17)
      A multi-volume historical series for adolescents, co-edited by Jon Butler and Harry S. Stout, Oxford University Press.
    - Religion in Colonial America, 1998-1999 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
      A volume in the Religion in American Life series.
    - Religion issue, William and Mary Quarterly, Jon Butler, guest editor, 1995-1996 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Encyclopedia entries
    - "Religion," Encyclopedia of the New American Nation, 2004 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Smithsonian Atlas of American History, 1989-1996 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Reviews by Butler for Harper & Row; Holt, Rinehart and Winston; and numerous university presses, 1983-1987 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Reviews by Butler, 1974-1983, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
    Includes review of "Witchcraft, Healing and Historians' Crazes"
  - Submission critiques by American Historical Review, 1976-1979 (Box 28, Folder 8)
- Electronic Records, 1994-2011; Series V (Reel 29)
  Electronic records include extensive email correspondence; materials related to Butler's writing and publishing career; speech, lecture and conference session notes; teaching files; personal papers; and files pertaining to his tenure as both Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences and Acting University Librarian at Yale.
  Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
  - Electronic records, 1994-2011